Joao Moreira

Exeter, UK

joaosomoreira@gmail.com

joaosomoreira.com

**** +44 7437467596

Professional Summary

Software Engineer with seven years' experience of programming, designing, and delivering reliable, scalable and tested applications, meeting both customer and business needs. Experience with direct to customer and B2B projects. Comfortable working in teams of any size

Javascript	HTML, Styled Components	PHP
Typescript	CSS Modules, SASS, LESS	Golang
React, React SSR	Webpack, Gulp, Parcel	Python
Redux, Alt.js	Karma, Jest, Jasmine	Java
GraphQL, Apollo Client	TDD / BDD, DDD	Jenkins
Node.js	Micro services architecture	Docker
Angular	Continuous Integration	AWS
Ionic, Cordova	Continuous Deployment	Serverless

Experience

Lead Front-End Developer

Funeral Guide | January 2019 - Present

- Upon joining the company, I established the technology stack for the Frontend, designing, architecting, and developing all the necessary features for launching the Arranger web application in only 2 months.
- Lead the Frontend development team (varying in size between 3 to 7 people) through a series of successful work sprints implementing major features including inventory management and invoicing.
- Provide domain knowledge and technical direction to the entire product team and share Scrum Master responsibilities with the Lead Backend Developer.
- Developed and launched a small reporting gateway to monitor events on the Frontend using Go.
- Perform 1-to-1s, conflict resolution and technical mentorship to members of the Frontend team.

React, ES6, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo Client, PHP, CQRS, Go, Lambda

Senior Front-End Developer

Oneserve Ltd. | October 2017 - December 2018

- Designed, developed, and launched a mobile application from proof of concept to production.
- Implemented the infrastructure around the mobile application leveraging a number of AWS services, including Cognito, DynamoDB, API Gateway and Lambda, all deployed via Serverless.
- Developed the continuous deployment pipeline to validate, build and deploy the mobile application directly to the App Store and Google Play.
- Provided technical direction and mentorship to team members.
- Made open source contributions to Cordova plugin repositories and Ionic Framework tools.

Typescript, Angular 4, Ionic, Redux, AWS, Java, Jenkins

Joao Moreira

Senior Web Developer

Sound in Theory | August 2016 - October 2017

- Developed and launched several websites and storefronts using multiple PHP frameworks.
- Designed, architected, and launched the technology replacement of a back-office quoting engine.
- Designed and built an automated contact form testing framework.

React, Flux, FuelPHP, Magento 2, Laravel, Node.JS, Selenium, Gulp, Apache, Nginx

Software Developer

ManyWho Inc. | September 2014 - June 2016

- Contributed to the development of a UI engine to execute and display ManyWho Flows.
- Collaborated with a senior developer in the design, development and launch of a Draw Tool to build workflows.
- Created and launched a small Python Web Service that converts platform metadata into Lua code.
- Designed and implemented workflow solutions using the ManyWho Flow platform and supporting customers on their workflow projects.

React, ES6, Alt.js, Python, Lua

Front-End Developer

blur Group | April 2014 - August 2014

- Contributed to the development of the Frontend of platforms and dashboards for customers' use.
- Performed a number of styling and user experience improvements to customer dashboards.

AngularJS, LESS, jQuery

Software Engineer

Betweien | March 2013 - April 2014

- Developed several websites, web and mobile applications, including management of the remote servers where all the applications developed were hosted.
- Managed all server infrastructure and oversaw the deployment of mobile applications.

HTML5, Canvas, jQuery, PHP, Apache

Education

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal BSC Computer Engineering | September 2008 - October 2012

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal iOS Development Course (27 hours) | March 2014 - April 2014